《007系列之诺博士》
(皇后俱乐部 只准会员进入)
好了 我有一副好牌
That's it! Hundred honors and 90 below.
做得好 我输了
Nicely done,Strangways. I have to give it to you.
我得离开一下 来一巡酒 我请客
I must leave you for a few minutes. Order a round on my chit,porfessor.
可恶! 你每天非得在这时候停手吗?
Damn it all ! Must you break off at this time every evening?
对不起
Sorry, general.
我上司习惯每天在这时候打电话找我
My director is a creature of habit. I get a call every day at this time.
快回来 别让我们久等
Harry back before the cards get cold.
二十分钟 别乘我离开时做手脚
Twenty minutes. Don't doctor any hands while I'am away.
我们要一样的酒
Same again.
谢谢
Bless you, master.
快点
Hurry, man! Hurry!
快离开这里
Get away quick!
(斯崔奇威家信箱)
W6N, W6N, W6N
W6N, W6N, W6N...
呼叫G7W
Calling G7W.
听到吗?请答话
How do you hear me? Over.
G7W 伦敦 G7W 伦敦 我们听到 请答话
G7W, London. G7W, London. Receiving you. Over.
准备好传递讯息
Stand by to transmit.
等等 暂停
Wait. Out.
这里
Here.
(克拉布岛 诺博士)
W6N 请答话
Hello, W6N, report my signals. Over.
Hello, W6N. Over.
给讯息部主管 很紧急的
Foreman of Signals.Urgent.
对 找MI6无线电安全控制部
Right. Get me MI6 radio security control.
什么事?
What is it?
与京士顿的W6N中断了 中断了还是联络不上?
Kingston, Jamaica broke contact. Broken of faded?
是中断 通讯的电波还没截断
Broken. Carrier wave is still established.
你已检查频道吗? 检查了 但没有反应
Did you check both frequencies? Yes, sir. No joy on eithier.
继续尝试 联络上后告诉我
Keep trying. Let me know when they come up again.
W6N请答话
Hello? Hello, W6N, report my signals. Over.
我是通讯主管 长官 牙买加中断了通讯
Foreman of Signals, sir. Jamaica's broken off mid-transmission.
不是技术故障
No, sir. It's not a technical fault.
是
Yes, sir.
你会告诉他吗?太好了
Will you tell him, sir? Very good.
(驻伦敦大使)
抱歉 你是会员吗? 不是 我找詹姆斯邦德先生
Excuse me, are you a member? No, i'm looking for Mr. James Bond.
请问你贵姓? 请你把我的名片给他
What name should I say, sir? Just give him my card, will you?
想把外套放在那里吗?
Would you like to leave your coat over there, sir?
投注20万
200,000 à la banque.
跟 跟
Suivi. Suivi.
揭牌 揭牌
Carte. Carte.
7点
Sept à la banque.
投注20万
200,000 à la banque.
跟 也跟
Suivi. Banco suivi.
揭牌 揭牌
Carte. Carte.
八点
Huit à la banque.
跟 照样跟
Suivi. C'est suivi.
你们会负责支付差额吗? 是的 小姐 请换筹码
The house will cover the difference? Oui, madame. Changeur, s'il vous plaît.
揭牌 揭牌
Carte. Carte.
九点 我还需要换一千元筹码
Neuf à la banque. I need another thousand.
小姐 我很佩服你的勇气
I admire your courage, Miss
我叫席维亚特奇
Trench. Sylvia Trench.
先生 我佩服你的运气
I admire your luck, Mr
我叫邦德
Bond.
詹姆斯邦德
James Bond.
邦德先生 你介意我把投注限额提高吗?
Mr. Bond, would you care to raise the limit?
我不反对 别这样 小姐 没有必要这样做
I have no objections. Pas possible, madame. Ce n'estpas légal.
照样 照样跟，先生
Now. C'est suivi, monsieur.
看来你想取胜 可能吧
Looks like you're out to get me. It's an idea, at that.
八 八点
Eight. Huit à la banque.
九点
Neuf à la banque.
抱歉 谢谢
Excuse me, sir? Thank you.
我得走了
Andre, I must pass the shoe.
请见谅 那是很重要的事 谢谢
I hope you'll forgive me, but it's most important. Thank you.
代我拿去兑换好吗?
Have those changed, will you?
你这么快离开 实在太可惜了 事情刚开始变得有趣
Too bad you have to go, just as things were getting interesting.
对 告诉我 特奇小姐 你有什么别的嗜好?
Yes. Tell me, Miss Trench, do you play any other games?
我是指除了玩扑克牌外
I mean besides chemin de fer?
高尔夫球
Golf, amongst other things.
那明天下午吧 明天?
Temorrow afternoon, then. Temorrow?
接着我们还能一起吃晚饭呢
We could have dinner afterwards, perhaps?
听起来很吸引人
Sounds tempting.
我明天答覆你好吗?
May I let you know in the morning?
好
Splendid.
我的电话号码在名片上
My number's on the card.
请看看他是否在那里 好吗?
See if he's there, will you?
你往哪去了? 为了找你 我找遍整个伦敦!
James, where on earth have you been? I've been searching London for you.
007来了
007 is here, sir.
他很快会接见你
He'll see you in a minute.
钱班霓小姐!
Moneypenny.
什么? 是我
What gives? Me.
给我一点鼓励
Given an ounce of encouragment.
跟我吃晚饭时 你从不会穿这衣服
You never take me to dinner looking like this, James.
你从没带我一起去吃晚饭
You never take me to dinner, period.
我会的 但M先生会把我以军法处置
I would, only M would have me court-martialed.
罪名是非法使用国家财物
for illegal ues of goverment property.
讨好我没什么益处 但继续说吧 就现在吧
Flattery will get you nowhere, but don't stop trying. Now.
发生什么事? 关于斯崔奇威的 很严重
What's all this to-do about? Strangways. It's looks serious.
我们跟牙买加中断联络三小时
We've been burning the air between here and Jamaica for three hours.
去吧
In you go.
别忘记写信
Don't forget to write.
晚安
Good evening, sir.
现在凌晨三时了 你什么时候睡觉?
It happens to be 3 a.m. When do you sleep, 007?
不是在工作时间
Never on the firm's time, sir.
坐下
Sit down.
今晚我们跟牙买加中断联络
Jamaica went off the air tonight.
在开始程序进行的中途
Right in the middle of the opening procedure.
斯崔奇威失踪了
Strangways has disappeared.
她的新秘书也是 我们刚派她到那里不久
So has his secretary. She was new. We had just send her there.
斯崔奇威 在进行特别任务吗?
Was strangways on something special?
他在处理美国人的一个查询
He was checking an inquiry from the Americans.
他们投诉卡纳维尔角火箭 受到干扰
They had complaints about interference with their Cape Canaveral rockets.
他们认为干扰来自牙买加地区
They think it comes from the Jamaica area.
你知道"失准"是什么吗? 一点
Does "toppling" mean anything to you? A little.
是利用无线电干扰
It's throwing the gyroscopic controls of a guided missile off balance
导向飞弹的回转仪吗?
with a radio beam?
差不多
More or less.
价值五百万 瞄准南大西洋的飞弹
Five million dollars worth of missile aimed at a spot in the south Atlantic
落在巴西丛林中 已经很糟糕了
but finishing up in the middle of the Brazilian jungle is bad enough.
现在他们想利用火箭 环绕月球飞行
Now they're going to try orbiting a rocket around the moon.
美国中央情报局派人 跟斯崔奇威一起工作
The American CIA sent a man to work with Strangways.
他叫莱特 你认识他吗?
Fellow by the name of Leiter. Do you know him?
我听过他的名字 但没见过他
I've heard of him, but never met him.
他找到什么重要线索吗?
Has he found out anything important?
你问他吧 替你订了七时的机票到京士顿
Ask him. You are booked on the 7:00 plane to Kingston.
你还有三小时二十二分钟
That gives you exactly three hours, 22 minutes.
军械工匠
Armorer.
我会把背景资料送到机场给你
I'll have background papers sent to you at the airport
并且放在自我毁灭的袋子内
in a self-destructor bag.
让你在飞机上看
You can study them during the flight.
我想知道斯崔奇威 发生了什么事
I want to know what's happened to Strangways.
脱下你的外套
Take off your jacket.
把手枪给我
Give me your gun.
我也知道你还是用贝瑞塔 我已经说过了
I thought so. Damned Beretta again. I've told you about this before.
你告诉他 而且是最后一次
You tell him, for the last time.
这种手枪很轻巧 适合放在女性的手提包
It's nice and light, in a lady's handbag.
但威力不大
No stopping power.
你有什么意见?
Any comments, 007?
我不同意
I disagree, sir.
我用了它十年 不曾失手
I've used a Beretta for 10 years. I've never missed with it yet.
但它在你上次执行任务时卡住 害你受伤住院半年
No, but it jammed on your last job. You spent six months in hospital.
你编号中的两个0 代表你获授权杀人 不是被杀
You carry a doubel-0 number. It gives you a license to kill, not get killed.
我成为MI6的主管后 死亡率减少了四成
Since I've been head of MI6, there's been a 40 percent drop in casualties.
我想这情况持续下去
I want it to stay that way.
你得改用沃尔特手枪
You'll carry the Walther
除非你想离开前线工作?
unless you prefer to go back to standard intelligence duties.
不 长官 我不想
No, sir, I would not.
那你得用别的手枪 给他看看
Then from now on you carry a different gun. Show him.
这是沃尔特PPK
Walther PPK.
7点65密耳口径 威力就像砖块穿过玻璃窗
It's 7.65mil, with a delivery like a brick through a plate-glass window.
装上消音器后 只是些微减低射击速度
Takes a Brausch silencer with very little reduction in muzzle velocity.
美国中情局的人也使用它 谢谢
The American CIA swear by them. Thank you, Major Boothroyd.
谢谢 晚安
Thank you, sir. Good night, sir.
还有什么问题 007? 没有
Any questions, 007? No, sir.
好 祝你好运
All right. Best of luck.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
007? 是?
007? Sir?
留下贝瑞塔手枪
Just leave the Beretta.
钱班霓小姐 别跟007寒喧 他赶时间
Miss Moneypenny, forget the usual repartee. 007's in a hurry.
祝你好运
Good luck.
看 你让我打不中
There! You made me miss it.
你没有错过什么
You don't miss a thing.
你怎样进来的? 算了 反正你来了
How did you get in? Never mind. You're here.
我决定接受你的邀请
I decided to accept your invitation.
该是明天下午见面
That was for tomorrow afternoon.
你经常穿这样打高尔夫球吗? 我只是换些舒适的衣服
Do you always dress this way for golf? I changed into something comfortabel.
希望我没做错吧
I hope I did the right thing.
你没做错 只是选择了错误的时间
You did the right thing, but you picked the wrong moment.
我得立刻离开
I have to leave immediately.
太可惜了
Oh, that's too bad.
事情刚开始变得有趣
Just as things were getting interesting again.
你说你何时要离开?
When did you say you had to leave?
立刻
Immediately.
差不多立刻
Almost immediately.
纽约 泛美航机 已到达牙买加京士顿
Hello, New York. Your Pan Am 323 just landed in Kingston, Jamaica.
计程车 计程车
Taxi! Taxi!
好 去吧
All right, go ahead.
你先吧
Help yourself.
计程车 你是邦德先生吗?
Taxi! Mr.Bond, sir?
我是
Yes?
我叫琼斯 是政府派来的司机
I'm Mr.Jones. Chauffeur from Government House.
把我的行李留在饭店 我去查看订房记录
Fine, we'll drop my bags at the hotel. I want to check my reservation.
让我来吧 不 你只需看管行李
I can do that. No. You just take care of the bags.
政府总部吗? 是
Government House? Yes.
我想找秘书长 等等
Principal secretary, please. Hold the line, please.
谁找他? 环球出口的詹姆斯邦德
Who wants him? James Bond. Universal Exports.
欢迎来到牙买加
Welcome to Jamaica, Mr.Bond.
你的部门今早通知了我们
Yes, your head office alerted us this morning.
一起吃午餐好吗?一点如何? 好
Free for lunch today? One o'clock? That'll suit me fine.
你有派人来接我吗?
By the way, have you sent a car for me?
我不觉得你想有 正式的接待仪式
I didn't think you wanted an official reception.
对 一点见
Quite right. One o'clock then.
若我迟到几分钟 请见谅
Forgive me if I'm a few minutes late.
你想先到哪里? 政府总部 但不用急
Where to first, sir? Government House, but no hurry.
带我去观光吧
Just take me for a ride.
你经常开快车吗? 我说过不用急
You always drive this fast? I told you I wasn't in a hurry.
对不起 我想我们被人跟踪了
Sorry, sir, but I think there's some fellow trying to follow us.
那我建议你尝试摆脱他们吧
Then I suggest you try and lose them.
在下一个转弯右转
Take the next right turn.
在你的朋友来到前 快招认一切
Now, Mr.Jones, talk fast before your friend doubles back.
你替谁工作?
Who are you working for?
我不知道你在说什么 我被委派到机场迎接你
I don't know what you're saying. I was sent to meet you at the airport.
谁委派你?
By whom?
政府总部
By Government House.
看来不是
I don't think so.
把双手放在方向盘上 我是个没什么耐性的乘客
Both hands on the wheel! I'm a nervous passenger.
快出去
Get out. Move!
把你的手放在我能看见的地方
Keep your hands where I can see them.
站起来
Get up!
从实招来 好
Now talk. All right.
让我吸一口烟
Let me have a cigarette.
你去死吧
To hell with you!
警官 别让他离开
Sergeant, make sure he doesn't get away.
香烟中加入氰化物?
Cyanide in a cigarette?
很厉害 对
Fantastic. No less.
你有什么线索? 那是一辆赃车
Well, Duff, what have you got? The car was stolen.
我们还没认出司机是谁
We haven't identified the driver yet.
但他一定不是京士顿人
But he wasn't a Kingston man.
不管他来自哪儿 我抵达的消息已经泄露了
Wherever ha was from, news of my arrival leaked.
肯定不是我们泄露的
We didn't advertise it, I can assure you.
或许不是
Perhaps not.
看来有人在出售门票
It seemed someone had been selling tickets.
有什么我们能效劳?
Anything more we can do for you?
我想见最后跟斯崔奇威 一起的人
I'd like to meet the last people to see Strangways.
他跟玩桥牌的四个人道别后 没有人见过他
Nobody saw him after he left our bridge four at the Queens Club.
他们是谁? 登特教授
Who were the others? Professor Dent.
他是受人尊重的冶金学家 开设了一家实验室 背景清白
Metallurgist. Runs a test laboratory. Respected. Clean bill.
波特 前陆军上将 来这儿多年
Potter. General, ex-army. Been here ages.
先调查他们
Start with those.
要把他们带来问话吗? 不 我会私底下见他们
Want them brought in? Lord, no! I'll meet them socially.
今晚在俱乐部 我介绍他们给你认识
I'll introduce you at the club tonight.
好 我想看看斯崔奇威的地方
Fine. I'd like to take a look at Strangways' place.
我现在带你去
I'll run you up there now.
进去吧
Go on in.
对了 那里有血迹
Oh, yes, that's a blood patch.
他们说血型是ORh阳性 是她的血型
They've grouped it as O-Rh positive. That's her group, all right.
我们来到时通讯机还在运作
The set was still switched on when we came round.
我们曾尝试用那频道通讯 但没有反应
We tried to get through on that frequency, but it was dead.
以后也不会有反应 保安系统 被破坏后 所有频道都会更改
And it'll stay dead. All frequencies are changed when security's broken.
(地形结构 东加勒比海)
是登特实验室的收据
Receipt from Dent Laboratories.
斯崔奇威爱研究地质学吗?
Geology a hobby of Strangways'?
不是
Not that I know of, no.
跟斯崔奇威一起的是谁?
Who is the man with Strangways?
本地渔民
One of the local fishermen.
他刚才跟踪我 是吗?这可能是线索
He drove the car that tailed me. That so? That gives us something.
我会调查他 就这么办
I'll have a check made on him. You do that.
到俱乐部前我想先洗澡
I want to have a bath before I meet Pleydell-Smith at the club.
你吩咐的伏特加混合马丁尼 没有搅拌
One medium-dry vodka martini, mixed like you said, sir, not stirred.
还有什么吩咐吗? 没有了
Anything else? No, that's all.
太好了
Very well, sir.
斯崔奇威就这样消失了 真奇怪 是吗?
Curious, old Strangways just vanishing like that. Or is it?
他的秘书很友善
His secretary was very nice, very nice indeed.
你认识她吗? 我见过她
Did you know her? I'd seen her around, you know.
你们都不知道 究竟发生什么事吧?
I suppose none of you could throw any light on what happened?
他说过什么? 有没有露什么口风?
His conversation? Any hint?
他只说关于钓鱼和桥牌的事
I never heard him talk about anything but big-game fishing and bridge.
三周前他开始每天都去钓鱼
He started fishing three weeks ago and was out practically every day.
他因此付出代价 渔民都跟地球公司租船
Must've cost him something. These fishermen ask the Earth to charter.
夸勒尔的价钱最高 夸勒尔?
And Quarrel's the most expensive. Quarrel?
他是开曼群岛的人 在海港有一艘船
Cayman Islander. Keeps a boat in the harbor.
原来如此
I see.
不好意思 夸勒尔在哪? 他在那里
Excuse me. Where do I find Quarrel? Him.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是夸勒尔吗?
Your name Quarrel?
可能吧
Maybe.
我是斯崔奇威指挥官的朋友
I'm a friend of Commander Strangways.
很棒 我爱认识朋友的朋友
Ain't that nice! I like people who's friends of people.
你或许知道他发生了什么事
I thought you might be able to tell me what happened to him.
以我所知 没有事发生过
As far as I know, nothing happened.
除非你知道事情的另一个版本
Unless you know different, captain.
你用船带他到哪里?
Where did you take him in your boat?
看到吗?
See that?
那里是加勒比海
That there's the Caribbean.
我带他到那里钓鱼
That's where. Fishing.
我也喜欢钓鱼 我想租用你的船
I'm interested in fishing. I'd like to charter your boat.
对不起 我的船不租给别人
I'm sorry. It's not for hire.
看来我找错人了 对
Seems I came to the wrong address. That's all rigth.
若你不介意 我有事要办
Now if you'll excuse me, I've got business to attend to.
普斯费勒
Hey, Puss Feller.
可能是我的朋友弄错了
Well, if it ain't my friend what gets addresses mixed.
若你喜欢美味的食物 你就没有弄错
You got the right one now if you like good eating.
若谈话内容配合 我会喜欢美食
I do if the conversation matches it.
回到船只那儿 这里太多人了
Back at the boat, too public.
进去就不一样了 我跟你
In there, it different. After you.
好
Sure thing.
让我们单独聊聊 好
See we get a bit of privacy. Nothing but.
好
Nothing but.
坐下 不用了
Pick a seat. I'm fine.
好 你想谈什么?
Okay, mister, supposing you start the conversation. How's about it?
别挣扎了 普斯费勒可以跟鳄鱼摔角
Ain't no use struggling. Puss Feller wrestles alligators.
对 慢慢站起来 面向墙壁
Right! Up slowly and face that wall.
站住
Hold it.
放松一点 别紧张
Gently, gently. Let's not get excited.
替他搜身
Frisk him.
没发现
Nothing.
有趣 你怎会来这里?
Interesting. Where were you measured for this?
我的裁缝萨维露告诉我
My tailor. Savile Row.
是吗? 我的消息来自华盛顿
That so? Mine's a guy in Washington.
中央情报局的菲力斯莱特
Felix Leiter, Central Intelligence Agency.
你一定是詹姆斯邦德了
You must be James Bond.
我们站在同一阵线吗?
You mean we've fighting the same war?
我在机场看到你
I spotted you at the airport.
看到你上敌人的车时 我想自己一定弄错了
When I saw you drive off with the opposition, I figured I must be wrong.
夸勒尔是我的助手
Quarrel's been helping me.
希望你不会很难受 手有点痛 很高兴认识你
No hard feelings, I hope. Only a sore hand. Glad to know you.
他是这里的主人普斯费勒
That's Puss Feller. He owns the place.
希望他的厨艺比身手好 你试试吧
Hope he cooks better than he fights. You could find out.
还没有人吃过我的食物后死亡
Nobody died from my cooking yet.
∮ 轻轻松松跳起来 ∮
∮  It's so easy to jump up ∮
∮ 漂亮女孩走了过来 ∮
∮  Take a pretty girl, take a whirl ∮
∮ 挥舞着手跳起来 ∮
∮  And then do it again, again jump up ∮
∮ 搂紧了她跳起来 ∮
∮  Hold her very tight, then for all the night ∮
∮ 跳起来 ∮
∮  Jump up ∮
∮ 跳起来 跳起来 ∮
∮  Jump up, jump up ∮
∮ 牙买加 跳起来 跳起来 ∮
∮  Jamaica jump up, jump up ∮
∮ 牙买加 跳起来 唱起来 ∮
∮  Jamaica jump-up music ∮
∮ 欢乐永远在 ∮
∮  Jamaica never want to stop jump-up ∮
∮ 跳起来 跳起来 ∮
∮  Jump up, jump up ∮
∮ 牙买加 跳起来 跳起来 ∮
∮  Jamaica jump up, jump up ∮
∮ 牙买加 跳起来 唱起来 ∮
∮  Jamaica jump-up music ∮
∮ 欢乐永远在 ∮
∮  Jamaica never want to stop jump-up ∮
是这样的 卡纳维尔角的人很着急
There you are. Cape Canaveral is screaming.
他们不想登陆月球的计划 有任何差错
They don't want anything to go wrong with this moon-rocket launching.
你说斯崔奇威认为 干扰不是来自这里
You say Strangways didn't think the Interference was coming from here.
你该已经有点头绪 我曾非正式地调查
I suppose you cased the joint. I checked unofficially.
你们英国人对于越境的事 真的很敏感
You limeys can be pretty touchy about trespassing.
斯崔奇威和夸勒尔 调查了附近的岛屿
Strangways and Quarrel checked the offshore islands.
没有发现吗? 没有
You found nothing? Not a thing.
你们到了哪些地方? 几乎所有地方
Where did you look? Just about most everywhere.
火焰岛、克拉布岛和摩根暗礁 全都彻底调查过吗?
Fire Island, Crab Key, Morgan's Reef. Checked them all thoroughly?
除了克拉布岛 我们不能进入那里
Except Crab Key. We have no right to go there.
为什么? 那地方属于一个中国人的
Why not? It belongs to a Chinese
夸勒尔 抓住她和她的相机
Get her, Quarrel, and the camera.
小姐 晚安
Evening, missus.
你弄痛我了!
You're hurting!
船长想你跟我们一起喝酒
Captain wants you to have a drink with us.
你弄痛我了 你不是这意思
You're hurting me. You can't mean it.
晚安
Good evening.
你为什么想为我拍照?
Why do you want another picture of me?
在机场时我只拍了你的帽子 快叫这猿人放开我
I only got your hat at the airport. Tell this ape to let me go.
你为何要替我拍照?
Why do you want a picture?
我以此维生 谁聘请你?
That's the way I earn my living. Who pays you?
格林纳日报
The Daily Gleaner.
有什么我能帮忙? 你见过这女孩吗?
Anything I can do? Ever seen this girl before?
她有时会来这里 她骚扰你吗?
She comes here sometimes. She being a nuisance to you?
你要我赶走她吗?
You want me to get rid of her?
打电话到格林纳日报 问他们今晚有否派摄影师来
No. Ring the Gleaner and find out if they sent a photographer her toningt.
他们没派我来 我是自由摄影师
They didn't send me. I work freelance.
是吗?你为谁工作?
Freelance? For whom?
你
You
从实招来后他就会停手
Tell us and he'll stop.
她什么也不肯说 要我弄断她的手吗?
We don't get nothing out of her. Want me to break her arm?
下次吧
Another time.
下不为例 放开她
The second time nothing's come out. Give her her arm back.
快走 自由摄影师
Run along, freelance.
你会后悔的! 你们会后悔的 混球!
You'll be sorry! You'll all be sorry, you rats!
一人宁可服毒 另一人宁可手被弄断
One takes cyanide, another would have let her arm be broken.
两个都不肯招供 他们为何那么害怕?
Neither would talk. Who puts that sort of scare into people?
我想我们最好尽快查出来
We better find out but fast.
克拉布岛有什么特别? 为何我们不能到那里?
What's so special about Crab Key? Why can't we go?
那儿属于一个中国人的 他不让任何人进入
It belongs to a Chinese character. He won't allow anyone to land.
我曾派侦察艇视察
I had our naval reconnaissance planes tak a look.
他们只找到铝土矿和
They found nothing but a bauxite mine
雷达装置
low-scan C-H radar setup.
这些东西不违法
But there's nothing illegal about that.
我很害怕到克拉布岛
That Crab Key scares me plenty.
我的朋友到那里找贝壳
Friends of mine went there after seashells.
但却遇上麻烦 再没有回来
Only trouble, they never came back again.
本地的渔民都不会到那里
None of the local fishermen will go there.
斯崔奇威指挥官和我 在晚上潜入
Commander Strangways and me slipped in at night.
他拿了样本后 我们就离开 别再到那儿了
He take samples and we came back. Don't do to hang about there.
什么样本? 一些石块、沙和海水
What kind of samples? Bits of rock, sand, water.
原来这样 我开始对 克拉布岛产生兴趣
I see. Crab Key begins to interest me.
你们对那中国人 还有什么认识?
What else do we know about this Chinese gentleman?
没有 只知道他的名字叫诺博士
Nothing much, except his name. Dr.No.
(登特教授办公室询问处)
我想见登特教授 你有预约吗?
I'd like to see Professor Dent. Have you an appointment, sir?
告诉他是昨天认识的 詹姆斯邦德
Tell him it's James Bond. We met yesterday.
好 他在实验室里
Very well. He's somewhere in the lab.
登特教授在吗?
Is Professor Dent there?
不用了
Never mind.
教授 早安
Good morning, professor.
有什么能为你效劳?
Mr.Bond. Anything I can do for you?
我到过斯崔奇威的办公室 他有你的收据
Yes, I came across this in Strangways' office. Your receipt.
对 你能告诉我是怎么一回事?
Yes, that's right. Can you tell me anything about it?
斯崔奇威是个可怜的 业余地质学家
Poor old Strangways. Bit of a bug of his, this amateur geology.
他把石块样本拿来化验 说它们很有价值
He brought rock samples in for testing, convinced they were valuable.
真的吗?
Were they?
当然不是 那些只是低价的黄铁
No, of course not. Just low-grade iron pyrites.
能让我看看吗?
Can I see them?
不 我把它们扔掉了
No, I threw them away.
你知道他在哪里找到它们吗? 不 他没有说
Do you know where he found them? No,he didn't say.
是克拉布岛吗? 肯定不是
Crab Key, perhaps? Definitely not.
为何这么肯定?
Why so certain?
在地质学上是不可能的
Not geologically possible.
谢谢 感谢你与我谈了这么久
Thank you very much. It's kind of you to spare me your time.
不用客气
You're very welcome, Mr.Bond.
教授?
Professor?
请还给我
Allow me.
早安
Morning.
我得到克拉布岛 你知道程序吧
I've got to get to Crab Key. You know the procedure.
没时间了 我会负责
There's no time for that. I'll take responsibility.
希望你知道自己在做什么 走吧!
I hope you know what you're doing. Come on!
我发了电报 他们在等我 去吧
I radioed. They're expecting me. Go ahead.
坐下
Sit down.
为何你不遵照我的规定 在白天来见我?
Why have you disobeyed my strictest rule and come in daylight?
我一定要这样做 今早邦德来找我
I had to. Bond came to see me this morning.
我知道 我下令要杀死他 为何他还活着?
I know, I gave orders that he should be killde. Why is he still alive?
我们的任务失败了
Our attempts failed.
你的任务失败了 我不喜欢失败
Your attempts failed, I do not like failure.
你不会再让我失望吧 教授?
You are not going to fail me again, professor?
不会 我是来警告你
No. I came to warn you.
警告我?
Warn me?
告诉你
Tell you.
邦德发现斯崔奇威 从克拉布岛取得石头样本
Bond discovered those rock samples of Strangways' came from Crab Key.
他不是傻子 他很快会到的
He's not a fool. He's sure to come out here.
希望不是 若他来了 你要负责
I hope not. If he does, I shall hold you responsible.
你明白吗?
I make myself clear?
很明白
Yes, quite clear.
到桌子旁边
Go to the table.
你看到笼子内有什么吗?
You see what is in the cage?
把它拿起来
Pick it up.
拿起来
今晚
Tonight.
我想发电报 好的
I'd like to send a cable. Yes, of course.
你订的车子已送来了
The car you ordered, it's been delivered.
在五号停车场
It's in number five parking lot.
谢谢 晚安 晚安
Thank you. Good night. Good night, Mr. Bond.
早安 潘德史密斯 早安 邦德
Morning, Pleydell-Smith. Morning, Bond.
抱歉打扰你 但我需要一些资料
Sorry to trouble you, but I need some information.
有关诺博士 和克拉布岛的所有资料
All you have on Dr. No and Crab Key.
塔罗小姐 拿诺博士的档案来
Miss Taro, bring me the files on Dr. No.
坐下 你对这个岛有什么认识?
Sit down. What do you know about the island?
认识不多 除了那儿有铝土矿
Not much, except there's a bauxite mine there.
诺博士把那儿 当作集中营般管理
Dr. No runs it like a concentration camp.
我听到有趣的传闻 没有人正式投诉
I've heard funny rumors, but no one's ever complained officially.
塔罗小姐 放在这儿好了
Miss Taro, just leave them here.
很抱歉 我找不到资料
I'm very sorry, but we can't find them anywhere.
什么意思?谁最后看过它?
What do you mean? who had them last?
两个档案都被斯崔奇威拿走了
Commander Strangways. Both files.
好的
All right, Miss Taro.
真讨厌 档案就这么消失了
Damn nuisance, their disappearing like that.
相反地
On the contrary.
档案没消失我才感到奇怪
I'd have been surprised if they hadn't.
那包裹用外交邮袋 由伦敦空运抵达
That came for you from London in the plane, in the diplomatic pouch.
来自家乡的礼物
Present from home.
可以从那出去吗?
can I get out that way?
顽皮的习惯 从钥匙孔偷听?
That's a naughty little habit. Listening at keyholes?
我没有 我只是在寻找档案
I wasn'n listening. I was looking for those files.
找不到东西 我总要被责怪
Anything that can't be found, I get the blame.
算了吧 已经不重要了
Forget it. I'm sure it's not very important anyhow.
我不想你整个下午在找档案
I'd hate to think you'll spend the afternoon looking for them.
不 这个下午我休假
No. I have the afternoon off.
真巧合 我也是 你何不带我在这小岛观光?
There's a coincidence. So have I. Why not show me around the island?
陌生人的邀请 我是否该答应?
What should I say to an invitation from a strange gentleman?
你该答应
You should say yes.
或许吧
I should say maybe.
或许三点来我的饭店?
Three o'clock at my hotel, maybe?
或许吧
Yes, maybe.
好
Good.
发光的罗盘启动它 拿着
The luminous dial activates it. Hold this.
斯崔奇威指挥官 将样本放在哪儿?
Where did Commander Strangways place those samples?
大约是你站着的位置 很好
About where your feet is. Good.
你好 掉了东西吗?
Hi there. Lose something?
看看盖格指数
Take a look at this Geiger reading.
斯崔奇威从克拉布岛 带回来的样本具放射能
Those samples Strangways brought back from Crab Key were radioactive.
登特却说是一文不值的矿石
Yet Dent told me they were worthless chunks of iron ore.
他不是糟透的教授就是说谎
He's either a bad professor or a poor liar.
我想知道他究竟是哪一个 你 最快何时可带我们到克拉布岛?
I intend to find out which. How soon can you get us to Crab Key?
船长 情形是这样的
Well, it's like this, captain.
斯崔奇威指挥官已拿了 各个岛的样本
Commander Strangways, he done take samples of all the island.
我们先从最近的 岛屿开始好吗?
Supposing we check the nearest ones first?
不 我对克拉布岛有兴趣
No. I'm interested in Crab Key.
我曾带他到那儿 我们安全离开
I took the commander there, and we got away without trouble.
我们不应经常测试 一个人的运气
It don't do for a man to tempt providence too often.
那儿有龙
You see, there's a dragon.
什么?
What?
当地人的传说 可能是诺博士传出来的
Native superstition. Started by Dr. No, probably.
我们不想逼你
All right. We don't want to force you.
只要你为我们引路 莱特和我会在晚上进去
Leiter and I will go over after dark if you'll give us directions.
我用鼻子、耳朵和第六感
I get my directions from my nose
来辨别方向
my ears, from my instincts.
无论如何 七点我会到
Anyway, I'll be here about 7.
好
Fine.
邦德先生 你有留言
Mr. Bond, there's a telephone message for you.
强尼 你把它放在哪儿? 就在这儿
Johnny, what have you done with it? It's right here.
喂
Hello?
邦德先生 我在想
Oh, Mr.Bond. I was thinking.
我想你来我家接我
Why don't you collect me at my apartment?
我的家在山上 很舒适和美丽
It's lovely up here in the mountains. Nice and cool.
好的 你从京士顿的皇室港路走
All right. You leave the Port Royal Road out of Kingston.
沿着文特沃思路 直至看到水泥工厂
Then along the Wentworth Road until you get to the cement factory.
然后左转
Then you turn left.
沿路上山 在另一边
Follow the road up the hill, down the other side
大约两里远 在左边
and two miles further on, on the left
马真塔路2391号
Magenta Drive, 2391.
我会等你
I'll be waiting for you.
怎会发生这种事?
How did it happen?
我想他们在出席葬礼的路上
I think they were on their way to a funeral.
等等
Just a minute.
可记得你曾邀请我?
You did invite me, remember?
当然 只是不知道你这么快就到
Of course. I just didn't expect you here so soon.
进来吧
Yes, come in.
我先去穿衣服
I'll go put some clothes on.
别因为我添麻烦
Don't go to any trouble on my account.
求求你
Please.
原谅我 我以为你想我来看景色的
Forgive me. I thought I was invited up here to admire the view.
我们其中一人该接听电话
I feel one of us should answer it.
你好 我知道 他现在在这
Hello? Yes, I know. He's here now.
我不知道发生什么事
I don't know what happened.
好的 我会拖延他几个小时
All right. I'll try and keep him here for a couple of hours.
好的 我要挂了
All right-I'll have to go now.
稍后再找你
All right. I'll call you later.
我看得出你喜欢过危险的生活
You believe in living dangerously. I can see that.
这是什么意思?
What do you mean?
头发湿透的坐在那儿 你会患上肺炎
Sitting around with wet hair, you'll die of pneumonia.
很漂亮 谢谢
It is rather beautiful. Thank you.
你经常束起头发吗?
Do you always wear it up?
你不喜欢这样吗? 非常喜欢
Don't you like it that way? Very much.
加上你的样貌 真是美极了
With your sort of face, it's wonderful.
我的背部怎么了?
What's going on behind my back?
没什么
Nothing.
看 双手在这儿
Look, no hands.
我肚子饿 出外吃东西吧
I'm hungry. Let's go out and eat.
我来做晚餐
I'll make dinner here.
不 我想吃意大利菜和听音乐
No. I'm feeling Italian and musical.
去蓝山餐厅吧
The Blue Mountain Grill.
我宁可留在这儿
I'd rather stay here.
独处乐趣更多
It's more fun alone.
但我不想你的玉手为我操劳
Yes, but I don't want you getting dishpan hands.
我喜欢烹饪
I like cooking.
算了吧 我可以用你的电话吗?
Forget it. May I use your phone?
你打电话给谁?
Who are you ringing?
计程车
Taxi.
我是詹姆斯邦德 请派车子来
James Bond here. Can I have a car sent to
马真塔路2171号
2171 Magenta Drive?
请尽快 谢谢
As soon as you can, please. Thank you.
我以为你开车子来 车子坏了 引擎有问题
I thought you came by car. Wouldn't start. Engine trouble.
这解释了
That explains
解释了什么?
Explains what?
为何你需要计程车
Why you need a taxi.
为何我需要计程车?
Why I need a taxi?
小心我的指甲
Careful, my nail varnish!
不用关灯吗? 不 我经常开灯
The lights. No, I always leave them on.
发生什么事?
What's going on?
原谅我 督察 拘捕她
Forgive me. Book her, superintendent.
还有
And
小心她的指甲
be careful of her nail varnish.
放下它 教授 在你背后
Drop it, professor! Behind you.
我想你早晚也会出现
I thought you'd turn up sooner or later.
坐下
Sit down.
那女孩透露了 当然
The girl talked. But of course.
我在皇后俱乐部已怀疑
I was suspicious at the Queens Club anyhow
只有你见过斯崔奇威的秘书
when you were the only one who'd seen Strangways' new secretary.
接着在实验室
Then at the lab
你没有提及斯崔奇威的样本
you didn't mention that Strangways' samples
是具放射能的
were radioactive.
你非常聪明
Very clever, Mr. Bond.
你不知道要对抗的 力量有多庞大
You're up against more than you know.
杀死我 你会像斯崔奇威一样
Shoot me, you'll end up like Strangways.
你杀了他?
You killed him?
他已被杀 不管他是怎么死的
He was killed, but never mind how.
你为谁工作?
Who are you working for?
我告诉你 你也用不着这资料 我是
I'll tell you. You won't live to use the information. I'm working
这是史密斯魏森手枪
It's a Smith & Wesson
你已开了六发子弹
and you've had your six.
迟到总好过不来
Better late than never.
一切准备好吗? 两小时前就已经就绪
Everything ready? For the last two hours.
别担心 一切会很顺利
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
如你所愿吧
You say so.
但我却有不同的预感
Bottom of where my belly used to be tells me different.
我认为到克拉布岛 是很好的放松
For me, Crab Key's going to be a gentle relaxation.
想远离什么?女人吗? 不想再处于挨打位置
From what? Dames? No, from being a clay pigeon.
引擎只可带我们到这儿
This is as far as we go with the engine.
现在开始要靠风力和浆
Make with paddle and wind from now on in.
让我跟他一起去 不 我们说好了 由我来吧
Let me go with him. No. We settled that. It's my beat.
我已身不由己了
It's my head in the noose if anything gets unstuck.
卡纳维尔角发射火箭 只会延迟四十八小时
Canaveral can only wait 48 hours for that moon shot.
我们在十二点回来 若我们不回来 那就由你来
We'll be back in 12. If not, it's your beat.
你最好带海军来
You better bring your marines with you.
夸勒尔 若你见到龙
Quarrel, if you see a dragon
你先对付他 向他呼气
you get him first and breathe on him.
你喝了这么多甜酒 他会死得很高兴
With all that rum in you, he'll die happy.
最好放下帆 以免被雷达探测到
Better drop the sail in case their radar's on scan.
转向 船长 立刻!
Hard about, captain. Now!
把它盖好
Cover it up.
我们在天亮前 最好先睡一会儿
We'd better get some sleep before it gets light.
我会在那边
I'll be down this end.
∮ 芒果树下 ∮
∮  Underneath the mango tree ∮
∮ 啦-啦 啦-啦 啲 ∮
∮  La-la la-la dee ∮
∮ 守着月亮 ∮
∮  Come watch for the moon ∮
∮ 啦-啦-哒-哒 ∮
∮  La-la-da-da ∮
∮ 芒果树下 爱人伴我 ∮
∮  Mango tree, me honey and me ∮
∮ 一起吟唱 ∮
∮  Make bu-lu-lup ∮
∮ 芒果树下 ∮
∮  Underneath the mango tree... ∮
∮ 一起吟唱 ∮
∮  Make bu-lu-lup soon ∮
∮ 啦-啦-啦 啲-哒-哒 爱人伴我  ∮
∮  La-la-la dee-da-da... me honey and me ∮
∮ 芒果树下 ∮
∮  Underneath the mango tree ∮
∮ 爱人伴我 ∮
∮  My honey and me... ∮
是谁?
Who is that?
不用怕 我不该来这儿 你独自一人吗?
It's all right, I'm not supposed to be here either. Are you alone?
你在这儿干嘛?找寻贝壳?
What are you doing here? Looking for shells?
不 我只是四处张望
No, I'm just looking.
留在原地
Stay where you are.
我答应不会偷你的贝壳 我也答应
I promise I won't steal your shells. I promise you won't either.
留在原地 我到来的目的很神圣
Stay where you are! My intentions are strictly honorable.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
瑞德 全名是什么?
Ryder. Ryder what?
哈妮瑞德
Honey Ryder.
为什么你在笑? 没什么 这名字很好
What's so funny about it? Nothing. It's a very pretty name.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
詹姆斯
James.
你用小船驶到暗礁吗?
Tell me, did you use your sail all the way up to the reef?
当然 我一向如此
Of course. I always do.
那么他们会知道我们在这儿 他们有雷达
Then they'll know we're here. They have radar.
我的船太小了 他们发现不到
My boat is too small to be noticed.
我经常到这儿拾贝壳
And I often come here to get shells.
开始时他们想抓我 但抓不到
At first they tried to catch me, but they couldn't.
现在他们也不介意了
Now I don't think they bother anymore.
这次他们会
They will this time.
别理会它们
Don't bother with those!
别理会?
Don't bother?
很值钱的吗?
Are they valuable?
这个在迈阿密可卖得五十元
This one is worth $50 in Miami.
五十元
Fifty!
你答应不会告诉别人吗?
You promise you won't tell anyone?
我答应
I Promise.
快来看看 没问题 他是我的同伴
Come and take a look! It's all right. He's with me.
船长 你认为怎样?
Captain, what do you think of that?
怎么了?
What's the matter?
那是高速船只 找掩护 来吧
That's a high-powered boat. Take some cover. Come on!
他们在这儿
They're here, all right.
你们快出来 这就不会受伤
Okay, folks. Come out and you won't get hurt.
站起来 表露身分
Stand up and show yourselves
否则我们会开火
or we'll be forced to open fire!
快出来
Come on out!
我们知道你们在这儿 我们一直在等你们
We know you're there! We've been expecting you.
高举双手走出来
Just walk out with your hands up and you'll be okay.
这是你们的最后机会
This is your last chance.
他们只是吹嘘 别伸出头来
They're bluffing, but keep your head down.
好的 已向你们作出警告
All right! You've been warned!
这是最后通牒 别动
This is it! Lie still.
不会持续很久的 他们不知道我们在此
It won't last long. They don't know we're here.
开火
Fire!
你要出来吗?
You coming out?
好的
All right, then.
我们会带狗回来
We'll be back! We'll be back with the dogs!
全速前进
Full speed ahead.
我早说过这儿有问题
I told you there's something wrong here.
那是机枪 不是龙
That was a machine gun, not a dragon.
这儿也有龙
There's a dragon here too.
她说得对 你曾见过他吗?
She's right. You've seen it?
我见过 他有两个头 眼睛火红
Yes, I have. He had two great, glaring eyes
尾子短短 还有翅膀
short tail and pointed wings.
他会喷火 你不相信我?
He was breathing fire. You don't believe me, do you?
小女孩 我相信
Little gal, I does.
邦德先生 我们快离开这儿
I tell you, Mr. Bond. Let's get out of here.
听着 根本没有龙
Listen, both of you. There are no such things as dragons.
你看见的只是像龙的物体
What you saw was something that looked like one.
我在想他是什么
I'm trying to think what it was.
你如何知道那不是龙? 你对动物有多少认识?
How do you know there aren't? What do you know about animals?
你曾见过鼬跳舞吗?
Did you ever see a mongoose dance
或者蝎子因为中暑而刺死自己
or a scorpion with sunstroke sting itself to death
或者螳螂在做爱后吃掉丈夫?
or a praying mantis eat her husband after making love?
我不想承认 但我不曾见过 我见过
I hate to admit it, but I haven't. Well, I have.
她说得对
She's right.
他们走了 哈妮 你也要离开
They've gone. Honey, you're getting out of here.
我准备好了自会离开 绝不是在白天离开
I'll get out when I'm ready, and that's never in daylight.
这次你是 快点
This time you are, and fast.
你的船在哪?
Where's your boat?
拿我的鞋子来
Fetch my shoes.
看他们干的好事
Look what they've done!
都是你的错
It's all your fault!
很抱歉 回到京士顿 我会买一艘新船给你
I'm sorry. I'll get you a new boat when we get back to Kingston.
现在怎处置她?
What are we going to do with her now?
若你不介意 我知道一个藏身地点
If you like, I know a good place where we can hide.
这是个开始 留下不需要的东西 快点
That'll do for a start. Leave what you don't need. Quick!
好的
All right, all right.
我们定要走这条路吗? 这不会留下气味让狗追踪
Must we come this way? It throws the dogs off the scent.
可恶的蚊子! 用水涂遍全身
Damn mosquitos! Rub water all over yourself.
他们想吃芉
It's the salt they're after.
快点 他们来了 在那儿
Quick! They's coming! Across there!
割下一些芦苇 把刀子给我
Cut some of those reeds! Give me the knife.
去那儿
Over there.
他们更接近了
They're coming closer.
安静 有东西咬我的脚
Quiet! Something's biting my foot!
若你乱动 他们就会知道 我们在这 潜下去
If you disturb the mud, they'll know we're here. Get down.
他们好像有所发现
Look like they're onto something.
潜下去
Down. Get down.
为什么? 我一定要这样做
Why? Because I had to.
这家伙很在行 我们躲过 其他人 他还跟踪我们
The guy knew his business, trailing us after we'd let the others pass.
快离开这儿 你说的藏身处在哪?
Let's get out of here. Where's your hiding place?
在上面
Up there.
来吧
Come on.
(危险 不准进入)
你已经不那么臭了
You smell nicer already.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
快点
Mr. Bond! Quick!
现在怎样? 看这个
What now? Look!
那些是龙的痕迹
Those are dragon tracks.
看 这是他呼吸过的地方
Look! That's where he breathed!
若你想休息就休息一会
You ought to get some rest if you want to.
我留在这儿观察 他闻到我们的气味就会到来
I stay out here and watch in case he smells us and comes looking for us.
对 我跟你轮流
Right. I'll take the second watch.
我们在午夜就会离开
We'll be out of here by midnight.
我从不曾认识任何侦探
I never met a detective before.
你会拘捕诺博士吗? 有人会拘捕他
Are you going to arrest Dr. No? Someone is.
不可让他杀死任何来这儿的人
We can't have him trying to kill everyone who comes here.
他不只尝试
He doesn't just try.
我肯定他杀死了我的父亲 这是什么意思?
I'm pretty sure he killed my father. What do you mean?
我的父亲是海洋生物学家
You see, my father was a marine zoologist.
我们来到加勒比海 好让他研究贝壳
We came to the Caribbean for him to study seashells.
他去了克拉布岛后 我不曾再见他
One day, he came to Crab Key, and I never saw him again.
他们说他一定是溺毙了
They said he must have drowned.
但他是出色的潜水员 不会发生这种事的
But he was too good a diver for that to happen.
警方没有调查吗? 你的家人又怎样?
Didn't the police investigate? What about your family?
他们调查了很长时间
They investigated for a long time.
接着说他失踪了 假设死亡
Then they said, "Missing, presumed dead."
我没有其他家人 只有父亲和我
I haven't any family. There was only my father and me.
你单独一人吗?
You're here alone?
来此前你住在哪儿?
Where did you live before you came here?
世界各地
All over the world.
菲律宝、巴厘岛、夏威夷 只要是有贝壳的地方
The Philippines, Bali, Hawaii. About anywhere there were shells.
你一定念过书
You went to school somewhere.
我不用上学 我们有百科全书
I didn't need to. We had an encyclopedia.
八岁时我从A开始学习 现在已学到T了
I started at  "A" when I was 8, and now I've reached  "T".
我懂的事肯定比你多
I bet I know a lot more things than you do.
在京士顿的有人帮忙吗?
Didn't anyone in Kingston help?
我们以前居住的地方的房东
Well, there was this man who owned the place where we were living.
他让我不用付钱留宿一段日子
He let me stay on for a while without paying.
接着有一晚他进入我的房间
Then one night, he came up to my room.
你知道
Well, you know.
我弄伤他的脸 接着 他比我壮
I scratched his face, and then But he was stronger than I was.
发生什么事?
What happened?
我将黑寡妇蜘蛛 放在他的蚊帐内
I put a black widow spider underneath his mosquito net.
雌性的 他们最厉害
A female, and they're the worst.
过了一个礼拜他才死去
It took him a whole week to die.
我做错了吗?
Did I do wrong?
只要不成为习惯就可以
It wouldn't do to make a habit of it.
你有女朋友吗?
Do you have a woman of your own?
快点 这儿
Quick! Down here!
不论是什么 正朝着这儿过来
Whatever's coming, it's coming this way.
这次我想亲眼看见
This time, I want to see it.
快点 还剩下不到十二小时了
And hurry! There's less than 12 hours to go.
留在原地 全部的人!
Stay where you are! All of you!
留在原地!
Stay right where you are!
船长 若这不是龙是什么?
Okay, captain. If that ain't a dragon, what is it?
由柴油引擎推动的龙 忘了鬼神之说吧
A dragon that runs on diesel engines. Forget the spooks.
它驶近时 打那司机 我负责车前灯和车胎
When it's closer, take the driver. I'll take the headlights and the tires.
你留在安全的地方 来吧
You keep safe out of sight. Come on.
我说留在那儿 我很害怕
I said to stay there. I was frightened.
那么趴下
Then get down.
别看
Don't look.
快出来 将手放在我看到的地方
Come on out! Hands where we can see them!
还有那女孩 快
And the dame! Quick!
除非你想再挨一枪
Unless you want an extra navel.
等等 丢下手枪
Hold it. Drop that gun.
把手枪踢过来
Kick it away from you.
女孩留在原地 走向我 手放在前面
The girl will stay where she is. Walk towards me, hands out in front.
来吧 你想去哪儿?
Come on! Hey, you! Where do you think you're going?
抱歉我们没有花 走吧
Sorry we ain't got any flowers. Come on, let's go.
走吧
Come on! Let's go.
把刀子给我
Give me that knife!
放过他 别挡路
Leave him alone! Get out of the way!
进来 小心看着那个男人
Get inside! Keep an eye on the man.
小心 他们曾去沼泽 可能被污染
Be careful. They've been in the swamp and they're contaminated.
检查盖格指数
Check that Geiger reading.
他的指数是95 她是88
He's reading 95, chief. She's 88.
污染数字太高了 快替他们刷干净
Too much for the monitors. Scrub them down but quick!
转身
Turn around.
指数是72点8 泥土渗进了他们的衣服
Reading 72.8. The mud's soaked into their clothes.
好的 脱去他们的衣服
All right. Take off all their clothes.
他会怎样?
What'll he do?
我们感染了放射能
We picked up radioactive contamination.
先清洁那女孩 我们来下命令
Do the girl first. We give the orders here!
好 但想想办法 你过来
Fine, but do something about this. Come here, you.
这儿
Here.
使用高温高压射口
Use the higt-temperature jets. Full pressure.
她的指数是47 好的 到那男的了
She's reading 47. All right. Put the man through.
他的指数是40
He's now clocking 40.
仍然很高
It is still high.
指数38
Reading 38.
下跌到八 那女孩别动 第三阶段
Down to eight. Hold the girl. Stage three.
他的指数是18
He's now 18.
现在是八
He's now at eight.
基本上是零 她没问题了 好 叫他准备好
Practically zero. She's clear. Good. Get the man ready.
他的指数是四
He's got a count of four.
检查他的指甲 把手放出来
Check his fingernails. Put your hands in there.
他没问题 我会通知接待处他来了
He's okay. I'll notify reception they're coming.
已清除污染物 他们正在进来
Decontamination here. They're coming through now.
进来
Come in. Come in.
可怜的人 我们不知道你们何时会到来
You poor dears. We simply didn't know when to expect you.
本来以为是昨午茶时间 接着是晚餐
First, it was teatime yesterday, then dinner.
只在半小时前 我们才知道你要来
It was only a half-hour ago we knew you were on your way.
抽烟吗?有美式的、英式的 和土耳其式的
Cigarette? There's American, English and Turkish.
我是罗丝姐妹 这是莉莉姐妹
I'm Sister Rose. This is Sister Lily.
我们是来侍奉你们
We're here to make your stay plaesant.
很感谢你 但 你会想去看看房间
That's kind of you, but You'll be wanting to see your rooms.
早餐在准备中 然后你们会睡觉
Breakfast is already ordered and then you'll want to sleep.
博士下令在今晚前 不能打扰你们
The doctor left orders you're not to be disturbed until tonight.
你们一起晚膳他会很高兴 我该怎样告诉他?
He'd be delighted if you'd join him for dinner. Shall I say you'll be there?
告诉他我深感荣幸 好
Tell him I'll also be delighted. Splendid.
我知道他会很高兴 到了
I know he'll be pleased. Here we are.
这是你的房间
This will be your room, Mr. Bond.
这是你的浴室
This is your bathroom in here.
至于你
And for you, young lady
这是你的房间
this is your room.
这儿有洁净的衣服
You'll find fresh clothes in here.
希望会合身
I hope they fit.
因为至昨晚才知道 你衣服的尺寸大小
We didn't get your sizes till last night.
想要什么请告诉我们 随便什么
Ring if there's anything else you want. Anything at all.
例如两张到伦敦的机票?
Such as two air tickets to London?
我让你们好好休息吧
I'll leave you two dear people in peace.
吃早餐吧
Let's have some breakfast.
这时候你还有心情吃早餐? 因为我很饿
How can you eat at a time like this? Because I'm hungry.
我们不知道 何时再有机会吃东西
We don't know when we'll get a chance to eat again.
来 拿去吧
Here. Take this.
小心 这儿可能有窃听装置
Careful. The whole place is probably wired for sound.
你知道
Have you
你知不知道 他们会怎么对待我们?
Have you any idea what they'll do with us?
不知道
No idea.
没有门锁或窗户
No door handles or windows either.
这是监狱 豪华设备、一级服务
It's a prison, then. Mink-lined, with first-class service.
你感觉如何?
What's the matter?
我有点不舒服
I don't feel so good.
很想睡觉
I feel so sleepy.
可恶的咖啡
Damn coffee!
你怎么了?
How do you feel?
很想睡觉
Sleepy.
什么让我们昏睡的?
What made us pass out like that?
咖啡内下了药
The coffee was drugged.
该吃晚餐了 我们不想博士等候
Time for dinner. We don't want to keep the doctor waiting.
不用久等 准备好吗?
That would never do. Ready?
大概吧
I suppose so.
你表现很好
You're doing fine.
来吧
Come on.
我的衣着合适吗?
Am I properly dressed for the occasion?
很合适 适合什么样的场合?
Quite suitable. Suitable for what?
这边走
This way, please.
很高兴你的手也会流汗
I'm glad your hands are sweating too.
当然 我也感到害怕
Of course. I'm scared too.
自然一点 由我跟他说话
So be natural, and leave all the talking to me.
请进来
In here, please.
希望你们好好享受
I hope you enjoy your dinner.
过来看看
Come and look.
人工灯光
Artificial light.
我们可能在数百尺的海底下
We could be hundreds of feet beneath the sea.
这种海洋郁金香 只能在二百尺以下存活
Look at that. Sea tulips. They do not grow above 200 feet.
一百万元 邦德先生
One million dollars, Mr. Bond.
你在想它的价值
You were wondering what it cost.
事实上我确是这么想
As a matter of fact, I was.
抱歉我不跟你们握手 我的手遇上不幸事故
Forgive my not shaking hands. It's awkward with these. A misfortune.
你在欣赏我的水族馆
You were admiring my aquarium.
对 真让人印象深刻
Yes. It's quite impressive.
独特的科学技术 我亲自设计的
A unique feat of engineering. I designed it myself.
凸透镜 十寸厚 有放大作用
Convex glass, 10 inches thick, which accounts for the magnifying effect.
鲤科小鱼假扮成鲸鱼
Minnows pretending they're whales.
就像你在这岛上一样
Just like you on this island, Dr. No.
这看你是在玻璃的哪一面
It depends, Mr. Bond, on which side of the glass you are.
一杯马丁尼加柠檬皮 用摇的 没有搅拌
A medium-dry martini, lemon peel. Shaken, not stirred.
有伏特加吗? 当然
Vodka? Of course.
我们很快就要吃晚饭
We'll have dinner at once.
有太多事要讨论 时间又太少
There's so much to discuss, so little time.
诺博士 你干得不错
Well, Dr. No, you haven't done badly, considering.
命运是自己造成的
A handicap is what you make of it.
我是一个德国教士 和一个中国的大家闺秀
I was the unwanted child of a German missionary
的弃婴
and a Chinese firl of good family.
但我成为中国 最庞大黑帮的会计
Yet I became treasurer of the most powerful criminal society in China.
中国人相信混血儿是很少有的
It's rare for the tongs to trust anyone who isn't completely Chinses.
我也这么认为
I doubt they should do so again.
我偷了他们一千万黄金 逃到美国
I escaped to America with 10 million of their dollars in gold.
所以你有钱兴建这个工程
That's how you financed this operation.
使用核能是一个好主意
It was a good idea to use atomic power.
很高兴你处理得宜
I'm glad you can handle it properly.
那清除放射能污染设备 真的不错
I'd hate to think your decontamination chamber wasn't effective.
工作使我对放射能有深入了解
My work has given me a unique knowledge of radioactivity
但我也得付出代价
but not without costs, as you see.
你的权力来源使我方充满疑团
Your power source had our organization puzzled for some time.
他们仍很迷惘
They are still puzzled.
不再是了 我已寄出了报告
Not any longer. I sent a complete report.
自从要求送盖格仪器来后 你没有与总部联络
You've not contacted headquarters since you requested a Geiger counter.
已经有很多人在调查你
There are so many files open on you already.
我们、中央情报局
Our own, the CIA's
被你偷去金钱的中国黑帮
the one from the tong society that you robbed.
当麻烦到来时 你会发现 这儿是个小及贫乏的小岛
When trouble comes, you'll find this is a very small and naked island.
一个可牺牲的小岛
An expendable little island.
当我在克拉布岛的任务完成 我会毁灭这小岛并离开
When my mission in Crab Key is done, I destroy it and move on.
但求知欲不会减退
But the habit of inquiry is persistent.
你在想为什么?哪儿?何时?
I see you're wondering why, where, when.
我满足你的好奇心 因为你是
I only gratify your curiosity because you're the one man I've met
唯一欣赏我所作所为的人
capable of appreciating what I've done
并且没有向他人透露
and keeping it to himself.
等等
Just a minute.
此事与这女孩无关
No point in involving the girl. She has nothing to do with us.
让她离开 她答应不会透露半句
Let her go free. She'll promise not to talk.
不 我要留下 我不想你在此
No, I'm staying with you. I don't want you here.
我同意这女孩与此事无关 带她走
I agree this is no place for the girl. Take her away.
我肯定守卫会使她大开眼界
I'm sure the guards will amuse her.
放开我
Let me go!
那是55年的香槟 打破它太可惜了
That's a Dom Perignon '55. It would be a pity to break it.
我较喜欢53年的香槟
I prefer the '53 myself.
笨手笨脚 你让我失望
Clumsy effort. You disappoint me.
我不是傻子 所以别当我是傻子
I'm not a fool, so please don't treat me as one.
将刀子放回原位
That table knife, please put it back.
我们不可能全都是天才 对吗?
We can't all be geniuses, can we?
使美国飞弹失准真的能
Tell me, does toppling American missiles
补偿你失去双手之苦吗?
really compensate for having no hands?
这是证明我们实力的第一步
Missiles are only the first step to prove our power.
我们?
"Our power?"
你丝毫不尊重生命 你该为东方人工作
With your disregard for human life, you must be working for the East.
东、西 那是指南针上的指标 两者也是蠢才
East, West. Points of the compass, each as stupid as the other.
我是特别执行组织的成员 特别执行组织?
I'm a member of SPECTRE. SPECTRE?
反情报、反恐怖主义、反复仇
SPECTRE:"Special Executive for Counterintelligence
反勒索特别执行组织
Terrorism, Revenge, Extortion."
权力的四大基石
The four great cornerstones of power
是由全球最具智慧的人操控
headed by the world's greatest brains.
更正 是具犯罪智慧的人
Correction. Criminal brains.
成功的罪犯总是胜人一筹 一定要这样
The successful criminal brain is always superior. It has to be.
为何成为罪犯?
Why become criminal?
我肯定西方 会欢迎你这种科学家
I'm sure the West would welcome a scientist of your caliber.
美国人是蠢才 我提出帮忙 他们却拒绝了
The Americans are fools. I offered my services, they refused.
东方人也是 现在他们要为犯错付上代价
So did the East. Now they can both pay for their mistake.
控制全球 同样的旧梦
World domination. That same old dream.
精神病院内充满自以为是 拿破仑或神的人
Our asylums are full of people who think they're Napoleon or God.
你一直想激怒我
You persist in trying to provoke me.
我本可在沼泽杀死你 为何不动手呢?
I could've had you killed in the swamp. Why didn't you?
我以为你不会那么愚蠢
I thought you less stupid.
通常阻碍我的人
Usually when a man gets in my way
但你很不同 你花费我的时间 金钱和努力
But you were different. You cost me time, money, effort.
你打击了我的组织和我的自尊
You damaged my organization and my pride.
我很好奇想知道你是怎样的
I was curious to see what kind of man you were.
在组织内 可能有职位适合你
I thought there might be a place for you at SPECTRE.
太过奖了
I'm flattered.
我喜欢进复仇部门
I'd prefer the revenge department.
我的首要任务是找出 杀死斯崔奇威和夸勒尔的人
My first job would be finding the man who killed Strangways and Quarrel.
不幸地 我对你判断错误 你只是愚蠢的警员
Unfortunately, I misjudged you. You are just a stupid policeman
而且运气快用完了
whose luck has run out.
诺博士 他们在控制室等候你
They're waiting for you in the control room, Dr. No.
不用急 他们还没开始倒数
No hurry. They won't have started their countdown check yet.
你这次不可逃脱的
You won't get away with it this time.
美国人已准备好 会面对任何难题
The Americans are prepared for any trouble.
我从来不会失败
I never fail, Mr. Bond.
我们怎对待他?
What do we do with him?
好好教训他 我还有话跟他说
Soften him up. I haven't finished with him yet.
你已放入新的燃料吗?
Have you got new fuel elements loaded?
全都准备好了
All ready, sir.
路障在三千尺外
The roadblock is 3000 feet away.
所有在该区的人后退 不准车子驶入
Everyone in that area's pulled back. No traffic allowed.
发射区现已很安全
The launch area is cleared for safety.
唯一可进入这区的 是防御房的
The only personnel within the area are the crew
工作人员和测试人员
inside the blockhouse and the test counter.
警号没有指示 但已接近倒数时候
The alarm hasn't been given, but the time must be near the count.
火箭的重量达二百四十顿
The vehicle is now at its full weight of 240 tons
全自动电晶体已安装在火箭内
and all automatic transistors have been put on the vehicle.
我们会启动一半能量三十秒
We will run up to half-power for 30 seconds.
控制连结解开了
Control interlocks free.
燃料12点5
Fuel elements, 12.5.
控制方面怎样? 控制杆在运作中
Control? Control rod actuators operating.
核心温度113
Core temperature, 113.
变压器? 变压器准备好
Converters? Converters standing by.
点燃计已启动
Ignition meters on.
放射能量? 指数121、141、109
Radiation? Counters 121, 141, 109.
能量稳定器? 能量维持在八十万瓦特
Energy stabilizers? Energy steady at 0.8 megawatts.
水星控制号已装上追踪系统
system of tracking stations are plugged into Mercury Control.
燃料?
Fuel elements?
燃料 张在哪?
Fuel elements! Where's Chang?
张 你在干什么?快到构籓
Chang! What are you doing? Get on the gantry!
快点
Hurry!
关闭 关闭反应堆
Shut down. Shut down reactors!
他们要决定作第二次尝试 或者决定放弃
This is where control should make a second go or no-go decision.
这是水星控制号 关闭反应堆的倒数
This is Mercury Control. The countdown for the
温度227 正在下降
Reactor shutdown, temperature 227, falling.
关掉变压器
Converters off. Converters off.
放射能指数
Radiation reading.
放射能是零
Radiation zero.
关闭程序完成了 反应堆安全了
Shutdown procedure complete. Reactor safe.
准备 我们会留在太空船控制中心
Stand by. We'll stay on spacecraft control
作最后倒数
for final countdown.
这是水星控制号
This is Mercury Control.
检查显示器 所有系统也没问题
Check indicates all systems are go at this time.
倒数时间是四分三十秒
The countdown is now four minutes, 30 seconds
继续倒数
and counting.
(危险程度)
这是水星控制号
This is Mercury Control.
太空船机师、发射台
The spacecraft pilot, the launch
紧急小组的追踪队员
the tracking crew in case of emergency
甚至气象员也说可以发射了
and even the weatherman, have given us the word  "go".
继续准备 大约两分钟后发射
Remain on standby. Approximately two minutes to go.
控制杆已准备好
Control rod actuators standing by.
变压器已准备好
Converters standing by.
调整电波准备作干扰
Synchronize radio beam for toppling.
Synchronizing radio beam for toppling.
干扰电波已经调节
Radio beam synchronized for toppling.
现在指数是零
Zero in your mark now.
我们留在水星控制号 作最后倒数
We will stay on Mercury Control for final countdown.
准备
Stand by.
用尽全力 燃料21
Run to full power. Fuel elements, 21.
各部门注意
Attention, all controls.
现在进入发射阶段
Going into operation now.
已下了决定
Control has been made.
脐带式管苐已收回
The umbilical is retracted.
一切运作正常
All elements of progress and operation are in good condition
可以发射火箭
for the flight.
倒数进入T19秒
We are in T-minus 19 seconds and counting.
T15秒
T-minus 15 and counting.
十、九
Ten, nine...
八、七
eight, seven
呆子 住手!关上它!
Stop, you fools! Shut down!
二、一
Two, one...
零
zero.
(撤离此区)
危险
Danger.
发射了
Blast off!
已抛下高塔
The tower has been jettisoned.
火箭在灰色的天空中 真好
There's the rocked against that gray sky, and it's green!
我们可以看到火箭的外形 引擎在运作
We can see the outline of the rocket. The engines are burning.
你可听到那声音 很真实的感觉
You can hear that the roar still sounds good and true.
已到了第四个舱 非常热的火箭
It's above the fourth tank. It's a very hot rocket.
你可以看到蔚蓝空中有火焰
You can see the flame of it coming into clear, blue sky
开始闪闪发光
up in the sunlight, beginning to gleam.
非常好 稳定的攀升
Very good, steady climb.
所有系统也正常
All systems go!
哈妮
Honey! Honey!
跟我一起来的女孩在哪? 我不知道
Where's the girl I came in with? I don't know!
跟我一起来的女孩在哪?
Where's the girl they brought in with me?
十二号房 带我去
Number 12. Show me!
没有燃料了
We've run out of fuel.
我们该怎么办?
What are we going to do now?
可以游泳或
Well, we can swim or
或什么?
Or what?
过来
Come here.
邦德先生
Ahoy, Mr. Bond! Ahoy, Mr. Bond!
怎么了?你需要帮忙吗?
Well, well! What's the matter? Do you need help?
我颇肯定你不需要
I'm quite sure you don't.
既然你来了 请帮我们一把
Now that you're here, give us a tow.
将绳子抛过来
Throw us your line.